<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Pobega</title>
    <link>https://pobe.ga/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael Pobega</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:53:42 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pobe.ga/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing using Docker inside of a container</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/docker-from-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 13:53:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/docker-from-container/</guid>
      <description>This guide assumes familiarity with Linux command-line operations, Docker, and Fedora Atomic concepts.
For the last six years or so I&amp;rsquo;ve been running Fedora Atomic as my daily driver; an immutable version of Fedora that uses Flatpaks and containers rather than installing packages to the host OS. This means the base operating system is read-only, making direct installation of packages like Docker challenging within the host environment.
One complication is that so many projects use docker for building which is not supported inside of a container.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023 Update: Firefox &amp; Hardware Video Decoding on Wayland</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-video-decoding-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 16:58:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-video-decoding-2023/</guid>
      <description>Things have gotten a bit hairy with the H.264 codecs as of late. They&amp;rsquo;ve been removed from most distro&amp;rsquo;s Mesa implementation which has caused a headache for AMD users (such as myself) since AMD offloads video decoding to Mesa.
Thankfully you can still get hardware video decoding using Flathub&amp;rsquo;s Firefox Flatpak, ffmpeg and OpenH.264. I&amp;rsquo;ve deciding to document the process here since this whole thing was kind of a headache to figure out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring filesystem syncing with Rust</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/rust-filesystem-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 18:24:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/rust-filesystem-sync/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the writedisk crate (crates.io) for a while now to write disk images to USB drives. The interface is much nicer than using dd manually and it presents a list of USB devices and their human readable names to select from.
One thing that irked me was that there was a progress bar for copying the files but not for the filesystem sync afterwards so I decided to implement it myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox &amp; Hardware Video Decoding on Wayland</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-video-decoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 16:58:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-video-decoding/</guid>
      <description>Hardware video decoding is now available in Firefox (version 80 at the time of writing.) While there seems to be some experimental X11 support in testing (via the MOZ_X11_EGL=1 env var) it has been working (mostly) consistently for me in Wayland via the official Flatpak on Flathub.
The settings you&amp;rsquo;ll need in about:config are:
gfx.webrender.enabled=true gfx.webrender.all=true media.ffmpeg.vaapi.enabled=true media.ffmpeg.dmabuf-textures.enabled=true Optionally if you&amp;rsquo;d like to use system ffmpeg for VP8/VP9 video decoding as well:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Flatpak hits Flathub stable</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-flatpak-stable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 14:31:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-flatpak-stable/</guid>
      <description>Distro wars time: I&amp;rsquo;m a Fedora Silverblue user. I use it for both the ease of administration as well as the security benefits a completely containerized workflow provides.
One common issue folks trying to make the switch run into is packages being wholly unavailable - this can be resolved in three ways.
 Fedora Toolbox to create a Fedora container and dnf install tools. Flatpak to install graphical tools to be used on the desktop-side of the OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenovo Thinkpad T495s Review</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/thinkpad-t495s-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 22:37:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/thinkpad-t495s-review/</guid>
      <description>Earlier in 2019 Lenovo announced that they were adding new ThinkPads with AMD Pro processors to their lineup. As someone who&amp;rsquo;s spent the last few years trying to migrate away from Intel this appealed to me. After waiting months Lenovo finally dropped three new laptops: The ThinkPad T495, T495s and X395.
For the unaware, the AMD Pro CPUs ship with mobile Vega APUs (Vega 8 or 10 depending on the CPU configuration) which are integrated cards that pack a little more &amp;lsquo;oomph&amp;rsquo; than Intel&amp;rsquo;s offerings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Suspend Issues Caused By Intel 9260 Bluetooth</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/intel-9260-suspend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 11:15:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/intel-9260-suspend/</guid>
      <description>Note: This seems to have been fixed by upstream between 5.2.7 and 5.2.11 on Fedora 30 so this workaround is no longer needed.
Last week I received my Lenovo ThinkPad T495s, a new T-series line of ThinkPads from Lenovo that uses AMD processors instead of Intel. Everything so far is working perfectly (after getting a patched Systemd) except suspend.
(Update: see my full T495s review if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in reading more about the laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mythlogic Callisto 1413 (Clevo W740SU) Review</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/clevo-w740su/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 11:44:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/clevo-w740su/</guid>
      <description>The last time I splurged on a laptop was back when the Intel Core 2 Duo was the newest CPU on the market. Nowadays, I tend to just use EeePCs or budget i3 laptops to get my work done. With graduation approaching and senior projects looming I decided I wanted something powerful, and it needed to be fully Linux compatible. After a bit of research I decided on the Clevo W740SU, also known as the Callisto 1413 sold by Mythlogic, the Galago Ultrapro sold by System76, the Zeus Hercules as sold by CyberpowerPC, and various other names from other resellers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tunneling a connection through SSH</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/tunneling-through-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 14:23:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/tunneling-through-ssh/</guid>
      <description>So I finally arrived at school, only to find that my college has decided to block IRC on the campus wifi. Weirdly enough, they allow AIM/MSN/Jabber/Skype/Ekiga/etc traffic, but not IRC. According to the IT department &amp;ldquo;IRC is commonly used to spread viruses&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how valid that is, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t stop me from trying to connect to my usual IRC networks.
Luckily all they did was block the common (6000~7000) IRC ports, which meant that I could still get on any networks that offered alternate ports.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
