<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Michael Pobega</title>
    <link>https://pobe.ga/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Michael Pobega</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 18:24:03 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://pobe.ga/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring filesystem syncing with Rust</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/rust-filesystem-sync/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 18:24:03 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/rust-filesystem-sync/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using the writedisk crate (crates.io) for a while now to write disk images to USB drives. The interface is much nicer than using dd manually and it presents a list of USB devices and their human readable names to select from.
One thing that irked me was that there was a progress bar for copying the files but not for the filesystem sync afterwards so I decided to implement it myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox &amp; Hardware Video Decoding on Wayland</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-video-decoding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 16:58:29 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-video-decoding/</guid>
      <description>Hardware video decoding is now available in Firefox (version 80 at the time of writing.) While there seems to be some experimental X11 support in testing (via the MOZ_X11_EGL=1 env var) it has been working (mostly) consistently for me in Wayland via the official Flatpak on Flathub.
The settings you&amp;rsquo;ll need in about:config are:
gfx.webrender.enabled=true gfx.webrender.all=true media.ffmpeg.vaapi.enabled=true media.ffmpeg.dmabuf-textures.enabled=true  Optionally if you&amp;rsquo;d like to use system ffmpeg for VP8/VP9 video decoding as well:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firefox Flatpak hits Flathub stable</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-flatpak-stable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 14:31:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/firefox-flatpak-stable/</guid>
      <description>Distro wars time: I&amp;rsquo;m a Fedora Silverblue user. I use it for both the ease of administration as well as the security benefits a completely containerized workflow provides.
One common issue folks trying to make the switch run into is packages being wholly unavailable - this can be resolved in three ways.
 Fedora Toolbox to create a Fedora container and dnf install tools. Flatpak to install graphical tools to be used on the desktop-side of the OS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenovo Thinkpad T495s Review</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/thinkpad-t495s-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2019 22:37:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/thinkpad-t495s-review/</guid>
      <description>Lenovo&amp;rsquo;s first T-series AMD ThinkPads prove that they can stand with the big boys  Earlier in 2019 Lenovo announced that they were adding new ThinkPads with AMD Pro processors to their lineup. As someone who&amp;rsquo;s spent the last few years trying to migrate away from Intel this appealed to me. After waiting months Lenovo finally dropped three new laptops: The ThinkPad T495, T495s and X395.
For the unaware, the AMD Pro CPUs ship with mobile Vega APUs (Vega 8 or 10 depending on the CPU configuration) which are integrated cards that pack a little more &amp;lsquo;oomph&amp;rsquo; than Intel&amp;rsquo;s offerings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fixing Suspend Issues Caused By Intel 9260 Bluetooth</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/intel-9260-suspend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 11:15:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/intel-9260-suspend/</guid>
      <description>Note: This seems to have been fixed by upstream between 5.2.7 and 5.2.11 on Fedora 30 so this workaround is no longer needed.
Last week I received my Lenovo ThinkPad T495s, a new T-series line of ThinkPads from Lenovo that uses AMD processors instead of Intel. Everything so far is working perfectly (after getting a patched Systemd) except suspend.
(Update: see my full T495s review if you&amp;rsquo;re interested in reading more about the laptop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mythlogic Callisto 1413 (Clevo W740SU) Review</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/clevo-w740su/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2013 11:44:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/clevo-w740su/</guid>
      <description>The last time I splurged on a laptop was back when the Intel Core 2 Duo was the newest CPU on the market. Nowadays, I tend to just use EeePCs or budget i3 laptops to get my work done. With graduation approaching and senior projects looming I decided I wanted something powerful, and it needed to be fully Linux compatible. After a bit of research I decided on the Clevo W740SU, also known as the Callisto 1413 sold by Mythlogic, the Galago Ultrapro sold by System76, the Zeus Hercules as sold by CyberpowerPC, and various other names from other resellers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eee-Control and snd_hda_intel Troubles</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/eeecontrol-snd_hda_intel-troubles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2009 09:03:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/eeecontrol-snd_hda_intel-troubles/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I bought my Eee PC 901 I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find a way to manually control the fan; all of the tools that worked on my Celeron-powered 900 don&amp;rsquo;t work at all on my Atom-powered 901.
After a bit of Googling I found a program called Eee-Control, which claimed that it could control the Atom&amp;rsquo;s clock and fan speed. After trying and disliking the software I removed it from my system, but then I noticed a weird problem with my speakers &amp;ndash; they kept popping every time I initialized the sound!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Kernel (2.6.27.9) Upgrade on my Eee</title>
      <link>https://pobe.ga/posts/new-kernel-eee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2008 16:32:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pobe.ga/posts/new-kernel-eee/</guid>
      <description>So I upgraded my kernel from my very outdated 2.6.25-* kernel to 2.6.27.9, and I have to say I&amp;rsquo;m impressed.
I ditched my old MadWiFi drivers (contrib) for fully free and open source ath5k modules (built right into the kernel!), as well as having my ethernet built in (non-modular) and an improvement in boot time (under 2 seconds, but still)
I&amp;rsquo;ll be posting up a .deb and .config when I get around to it, I need to fix a little bit more (the webcam doesn&amp;rsquo;t work out of the box, I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to need to compile that into the kernel too).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>